NICKOLAS J. PALMER

palmer.743@osu.edu

412-609-4629

https://nickpalmer.dev/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nickolas-palmer-b17a9212b/

SUMMARY

Software engineer with experience in various software development areas including web development, web application automated testing, and game development. A recent graduate of The Ohio State University with a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Engineering, Nick has professional experience working for a government agency, small software firms, and a large automaker to help accomplish their technical goals.

EDUCATION

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH

B.S. in Computer Science & Engineering: May 2020

Specialization: Software Engineering

GPA: 3.159

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Dev Shop, Verona, PA

Part-time Software Engineering Intern, September 2018 - present

- Manage automated test builds that run against various client projects
- Developer of Angular 8 applications in a primarily front-end role

Honda R&D Americas, Raymond, OH

Information Systems Intern, May 2019 – August 2019

- Lead software developer on student team tasked with building minimum viable product
- Developed front-end of application with React Native, back-end with GoLang

Build In Motion, Aspinwall, PA

Software Engineering Intern, May 2017 – September 2018

- Developed automated tests against company's e-commerce platform consolidated 16 hours of manual testing into 15-minute script
- -Front-end developer on client projects using Angular with TypeScript

Ohio Department of Transportation, Columbus, OH

Traffic Operations Intern, January 2017 – April 2017

- Updated ODOT's Snow & Ice Traffic Report site used internally
- Used HTML, CSS, and JavaScript/jQuery

SKILLS

- -Languages used recently: Java, TypeScript/JavaScript, HTML/CSS
- -Languages used > 1 year ago: C, C#, GoLang, Visual Basic
- -Frameworks: Angular, React Native, Vue, Node.js, Protractor
- -Data-Visualization Libraries: Vis.js, D3.js
- -Databases: NoSQL, MySQL -Version control: GIT, SVN